CURRICULUM VITAE

NAME DR. AGGREY ADEM

ADDRESS P O BOX 90420-80100 MOMBASA

MOBILE 0721261415/0733551683

EMAIL <u>aggreyadem@gmail.com</u>

CAREER PROFILE

To contribute to teaching, learning and application of statistics through multi-disciplinary research and innovation at all levels of tertiary education and offer consultancy services in the field of statistical Analysis and modeling. I'm seasoned statistician with over 14 years experience in application of statistical tools in banking, health, business and education sectors.

KEY	I'm very pro efficient in a number of statistical software namely SPSS,
COMPETENCY	S+, R, STATA and Excel. I have vast knowledge in design of
	questionnaires and data collection, design and analysis of experiment,
	design and analysis of sample surveys, custom tailored statistical model
	building, general data analysis and interpretation and reporting research
	results.

EDUCATION			
Institution	Dates	Qualifications	
Jomo Kenyatta University of	JAN 2011-JULY 2015	Doctor of Philosophy in Applied	
Agriculture and Technology		Statistics	
		Thesis title: <i>Modeling</i>	
		Probability of Loan Defaults	
		in Commercial Banks in Kenya	
Kenyatta University	September 2004-July 2006	Master of Science in	
		Mathematics (Statistics)	
Kenyatta University	September 1999-August 2002	Bachelor of Education Arts,	
		Second class Honors upper	
		division	
Dandora Secondary School	Jan 1994-November 1997	Kenya Certificate of Secondary	
		Education, B	

EMPLOYMENT			
Employer and dates	Position	Duties and Key achievements	
Technical University of Mombasa	Lecturer, Department of Mathematics and Physics	i. Teaching and examination of under graduate students ii. Carry out academic research that integrates the needs of the community iii. Development of market oriented academic programs iv. Generate proposals that can win grants for the university v. Supervision of post graduate students vi. Mentoring of students vii. Initiate and participate in corporate social investment activities	
Technical University of Mombasa 1st August 2015 to 31st Janaury 2018	Director, Technical University of Mombasa Enterprises Limited (TUMEL)	i. Generate funds for the university by identifying business opportunities. ii. drawing plans for investment and mobilizing resources for investment projects iii. Research and identifies new government, corporate, foundations and private funding prospects. iv. Using knowledge of the market and competitors, identify and develop the company's unique selling propositions and differentiators.	
Technical University of Mombasa P O BOX 90420-80100	Lecturer, Department of Mathematics and Physics	viii. Teaching and examination of under graduate students ix. Carry out academic research that integrates the needs of the community	

1st August 2015 to date		X.	Development of market oriented
_			academic programs
		xi.	Generate proposals that can win
			grants for the university
		xii.	Supervision of post graduate
			students
		xiii.	Mentoring of students
		xiv.	Initiate and participate in
		AIV.	corporate social investment
			activities
Toolerical Hairransitas of	Assistant I saturnan	i.	
Technical University of	Assistant Lecturer	1.	Teaching and examination of
Mombasa	Department of Mathematics		under graduate students
D 0 D 0 V 0 0 10 0 0 10 0	and Physics	ii.	Carry out academic research that
P O BOX 90420-80100			integrates the needs of the
			community
1 st January 2012 to 31 st July		iii.	Development of market oriented
2015			academic programs
		iv.	Generate proposals that can win
			grants for the university
		v.	Mentoring of students
		Initiate	and participate in corporate social
			ent activities
Barclays Bank of Kenya	Credit Risk Policy Analyst	i.	monitoring performance of non
			secured portfolio loans book
P O BOX 30120 -00100		ii.	measure the performance of
Nairobi			non secured portfolio loans
			book against set triggers
15 th October 2010-31 st		iii.	advise the business on pricing
December 2011		111.	and packaging of the loans
December 2011			product
		iv.	research on the market trends
		17.	
			and competitors' information
			and performance
		V.	Statistical extraction, analysis
			and presentation of monthly
			and ad hoc reports.
		vi.	Initiate and participate in social
			corporate investment activities
D I D I CH	DI'E IA I		T1 (C 1 1 1 C 1 1 1)
Barclays Bank of Kenya	Debit Fraud Analyst	i.	Identify and pick fraudulent
D O DOM 20122 20122			transactions done using debit
P O BOX 30120 -00100		l	cards
Nairobi		ii.	Advise the business on the
			emerging fraud techniques
2 nd May 2009-14 th October		iii.	Train customers and point of
2010			sale outlet users on ways of

			nialzina fraudatara
			picking fraudsters
		iv.	Extract fraud related report,
			analyses and advise the
			business
		v.	Initiate and participate in social
			corporate investment activities
Barclays Bank of Kenya	Operation Performance	i.	Extract data and prepare
	Analyst		reports on staff performance
P O BOX 30120 -00100		ii.	Coordinate preparation of
Nairobi			management information pack
			across different operation
October2007- May 2009			centers
		iii.	Prepare annual budgets
		iv.	Initiate effective cost
			management measures
		v.	Initiate and participate in social
			corporate investment activities
Barclays Bank of Kenya	Management information	i.	Extract and process
	analyst		management information.
P O BOX 30120 -00100		ii.	Advise management on
Nairobi			performance of staff
15 th December 2006-		iii.	Initiate and participate in social
October 2007			corporate investment activities

Professional Bodies Memberships	I'm a member of the following Statistical bodies		
	i.	Kenya National Statistical Society (currently	
	the Secretary General)		
	ii.	International Biometric Society	

Curriculum	I have been involved in the development of the following academic		
Development	programs		
	Academic Program	Institution	
	Bachelor of Science in Mathematics and	Technical University	
	computer science	of Mombasa	
	Bachelor of science in Statistics and computer		
	Science		
	Bachelor of Technology in Renewable Energy		
	Bachelor of Technology in Applied Physics		
	Bachelor of Medicine		
	Master of science in Applied Statistics		
	Bachelor of science in Maths and Finance		
	Doctor of Philosophy in Statistics		
	Bachelor of Science in Mathematics	Pwani University	
	Master of Science in Statistics		

Other Academic	I have been an external examiner of post graduate thesis at the following
Engagements	Universities
	i. Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology
	Mombasa Campus
	ii. Pwani University

Workshops and Seminars	Workshop	Venue	Sponsor	Duration
Attended	Proposal	Technical	DAAD	Three days
	writing	University of		
	_	Mombasa		
	How to use	Sarova White	USAID	Five days
	Demographic	Sands Hotel		
	Health Survey			
	Data			

STUDENT SUPERVISION	I have supervised 25	undergraduate stude	ents and the follow	wing post
	graduate students	C		<i>C</i> 1
	Student Name	Research topic	Level	Status
	Joshua Kailong	Disclosure of	MSC	Graduated
		HIV sero-status		
		among people		
		living with HIV		
		and accessing		
		treatment and		
		care at Mombasa		
		county referral		
		hospital, Kenya		
	Josiah Kyalo	7.00	MSC	Graduated
	Mutuku	Effects of M-		
		pesa adoption on		
		financial		
		performance of small and		
		medium		
		enterprises in Mombasa		
		County		
	Solomon Mutava	An inclusive	MSC	Graduated
	Solomon Mutava	efficient and	MISC	Graduated
		cross validated		
		logistic		
		regression model		
	Florence Wambura	A comparative	MSC	Graduated

	study of Kernel		
	selection using		
	various		
	bandwidth		
	selection		
	methods		
David Nganga	Robust Poisson	MSC	Thesis
	regression verses		compilation
	logistic analysis		1
	for common		
	binary outcome		
Sammy Fondo	Modeling of	MSC	Thesis
Sammy Tondo	petroleum prices	MBC	compilation
	in using ARIMA		compliation
	and VAR models		
Domyl Oiveana		MSC	Data
Beryl Ojwang		MSC	Data
	barriers to HIV		collection
	testing and		stage
	counseling		
	among pregnant		
	women attending		
	Antenatal Clinic		
	in Mombasa		
	County.		
A amag Tayang	Influence of	PhD	The managed
Agnes Tsuma	financial	PIID	The proposal
	determinants on		is ready for
			presentation
	financial		
	performance of		
	commercial		
	banks		
Peter Murage	Optimal	PhD	Data
	threshold		collection
	determination		stage
	for the maximum		
	product of		
	spacing		
	methodology		
	with ties for		
	extreme events		
CL L D L	The effect of	PhD	The proposal
Clarkson Deche	The effect of	1 1112	
Clarkson Deche			
Clarkson Deche	occupational	Till	is ready for
Clarkson Deche	occupational internal fraud on		
Clarkson Deche	occupational		is ready for

	performance of state owned corporations in kenya	
--	---	--

Professional	Course	Group trained	Duration	Venue
trainings	Advanced data	Msc students of	Two days	
conducted	analysis using	JKUAT Mombasa		
	SPSS	Campus		
	Analysis of	Msc Public health	Two days	
	health data using	students of JKUAT	-	
	SPSS	Mombasa Campus		Kiziwi
	Statistical model	Msc Applied	Two days	Tourism and
	building in R	Statistics students of		Hospitality
		Technical		Centre
		University of		
		Mombasa		
	Using	PhD students of	Two days	
	Econometrics	JKUAT Mombasa		
	Models in SPSS	Campus		
	Survey Design	Staff of port	One day	PMAESA
		management		Conference
		Association of		room
		Eastern and		
		Southern Africa		
		(PMAESA)		

Consultancy Engagement	Firm	Task	Sponsor	Year	Role
	Notswago	Compendiums	FKE	2013	Statistician
	Consultant	of best			
		Practices			
		among Small			
		and Medium			
		Industries in			
		Kenya			
	TUMEL	Audit on	County	2016	Statistician
		Casual Staff	Government of		
		Head Count	Kilifi		
	TUMEL	Tariff Review	Mombasa	2016	Statistician
			Water and		

		Sewerage Company		
Dream Chasers Solution	Customer satisfaction Survey	Kenya Ferry	2017	Statistician
Verax Consultancy	Evaluation of Bwiti Resettlement Plan	Base Titanium	2018	Statistician
Verax Consultancy	End line Survey for project of improvement of water supply system in Chwele	Korean International Cooperation Agency (KOICA)	2018	Statistician
Verax Consultancy	Health education for the project of improvement of water supply system in Chwele	Korean International Cooperation Agency (KOICA)	2018	Statistician

List of Publications

- i. Kailong, J., **Adem, A.,** and Orago, A., (2019). Level of perception of HIV sero status disclosure among people living with HIV in Mombasa County. *Journal of Medical Case Reports and Reviews Public* **2(8)** 342-353
- ii. Kimari, F., **Adem, A**., and Kiti, L. (2019) Efficiency of various Bandwidth Selection Methods across Different Kernels. *IORS Journal Mathematics*. **15(3)**, 55-62
- iii. Mutuku, J., **Adem, A.**, and Muthara, M. (2019). Effects of M-pesa adoption on financial performance of small and medium enterprises in Mombasa County. *International Journal of Social Sciences and Humanities Research* **7(2)**, 293-301
- iv. Gichere, F., **Adem, A.**, and Adenya, R., (2018). Determining the mean differences in students' performance based on type of accommodation. *International Journal of Education and Research*
- v. Gikundi, D., **Adem, A.**, and Munywoki, M, (2018). Evaluation of efficiency of nyumba kumi initiative in combating insecurity in Mombasa County. *International Journal of Academics and Research* **1**(1) 5-12
- vi. Kailong, J., Orago, A., and **Adem, A.,** (2017). Disclosure of HIV sero status among people living with HIV in Mombasa county Referral Hospital Kenya. *Research Journal of Public Health* **3** 20-31

- vii. Chilimo, W., **Adem, A.**, Otieno, W., and Maina, W (2017). Adoption of Open access publishing by academic researchers in Kenya. *Journal of Scholarly Publishing* 49(1)
- viii. Mutava, S., Kiti, A., and **Adem, A**. (2017) Impact of Automatic Backward Model Selection Criterion on the Bias of the Parameters in Logistic Regression Model. *IOSR Journal of Mathematics* **13** (4)
- ix. Jeza, T., Chen, J., Lian, Z., **Adem, A.**, and Wu, X. (2017). Augments Rapamycin in Expansion of Alpha Fetoprotein Antigen specific stem cell like memory T cells in Vitro. *Pan African Medical Journal* **27**
- x. Chogo, C., Ibua, M.,Banafa, A., **Adem,** A.(2016). Factors affecting procurement law compliance in public secondary schools in Kenya. *Imperial Journal of Inter disciplinary Research* **2(11)**
- xi. Ochola, J., Ibua, M., Kilungu, J., Adem, A.(2016). The effects of Ethical Sourcing on Organization performance in the energy sector. *Imperial Journal of Inter disciplinary Research* vol2(11)
- xii. Kipruto H., Mung'atu J, Ogila K., **Adem**, A, Mwalili , Masini, E., and Kibuchi, E. (2015). Spatial Temporal Modelling of Tuberculosis in Kenya Using Small Area Estimation; *International Journal of Science and Research*
- xiii. Kipruto, H., Mung'atu, J, Ogila K., **Adem**, A, Mwalili , Masini, E., and Kibuchi, E. (2015). An Application of Deterministic and Stochastic Processes to Model Evolving Epidemiology of Tuberculosis in Kenya; *International Journal of Science and Research*
- xiv. Kipruto H., Mung'atu J, Ogila K., **Adem,** A, Mwalili , Masini, E., and Kibuchi, E. (2015). The epidemiology of tuberculosis in Kenya, a high TB/HIV burden country (2000-2013); International Journal of Public Health and Epidemiology Research **1(1)**
- xv. **Adem**, A., Gichuhi, A., and Otieno, R. (2014) Classification rate: Non parametric verses Parametric model using binary data; *JAGST* 1
- xvi. **Adem**, A., Gichuhi, A., and Otieno, R. (2012)Parametric modelling of probability of bank loan default in Kenya; *JAGST* **1**
- xvii. **Adem,** A. (2012). A monogram on Non parametric optimal estimation of the regression function; Lap Lambert Academic Publishing

CURRENT RESEARCH ENGAMENT

Anti microbial and immunomodulatory effects of acacia Rovumae and moringa oloifera extracts on selected diarrheagenic microbes. Researchers Dr. Jeza Tunje, Dr. Aggrey Adem and Mr. Ali Kanga

Community Involvements:

- Mentor at Dandora Secondary School and Highridge Secondary School
- With the help of Barclays, I sponsored 15 students in fees payment at Dandora secondary School
- BOG member at Highridge Secondary school for two terms (2011-2015)

■ BOG member at Dandora Secondary school for one term (2010-2013)

REFERENCES

Prof. Anthony Waititu
 Statistics and Actuarial Science Department

Kenyatta University,

P.O Box 62000,

Nairobi.

Tel No: 0704447775

2. Prof. Romanus Odhiambo Statistics and Actuarial Science Department

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture & Technology,

P.O Box 62000,

Nairobi.

Tel No: 0733341025

3. Beatrice Mwago Head of Payments

Barclays Bank of Kenya

P.OBOX 30120-00100

Nairobi

0721499141